## **Olawale Samuel Iwaloye**

Plot 19a Gbolahan Awe Close, Jubril Liadi Street, Magodo phase 2, Lagos State. Phone: +2348134437871 E-Mail: iwaloyeo@gmail.com

### **Professional Summary:**

Methodical, client-focused frontend developer with over 4 years of experience in web development Proficient with object-oriented programming languages as well as algorithms and data structures. Good interpersonal relations, strong communication skills, hardworking and high level of motivation. Recognized for developing bespoke applications that optimize business performance and generate positive customer reviews.

Enjoys collaborating with colleagues and building cultures of cross-functional working to provide a greater platform for the success of projects.

#### **Technical Skills:**

Languages / Libraries: Html5, CSS, JavaScript, React, Sass, React – Native, Bootstrap 4, and Semantic UI, Ant design.

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Node.js, Sublime Text.

Version Control: Git.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

FRONTEND DEVELOPER (Remote)
CODEGARAGE AFRICA JANUARY 2021 – SEPTEMBER 2021

Designed and integrated restful API's on an enterprise resource planning application (Fuse ERP) bootstrapped with React.

Worked on the payroll system for the fuse ERP as well as performance appraisal. Implemented the design of an e-learning app (Cerebro) to help facilitate the tutoring of developer newbies Developed and maintained responsive websites for clients at codegarage Africa.

# SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR/IT OFFICER HUMANI ALAGA HIGH SCHOOL NOVEMBER 2019 – DECEMBER 2020

Service and manage the computer systems within the school.

Educate the staffs of the institution on how to efficiently use Microsoft office tools such as Microsoft word and Microsoft excel to create, edit documents and also store important information. Recommend and acquire computer hardware replacements and upgrades.

Perform routine audits of system and software

Maintain an inventory of all the computers within the organization.

# FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER (INTERN) HOTELS.NG AUGUST 2019 – OCTOBER 2019

Implemented, documented, and maintained the finance Tracker application built for client Mitigated the development of UI screens for a car-parking assistance application using technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4, and JavaScript.

Involved in testing, debugging, implementing and documenting moderately complex programs. Worked on the client - side of a blog web application solely meant for kid's bedtime stories. Oversaw the management of the code-base using Git and assigned tasks to my team members

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER JARRISOFT SOLUTIONS LIMITED JAN 2019 – DEC 2019

Creating and building UI Screens from start to finish using CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap 4. Writing quality codes and testing for responsiveness of the web application screens Spearheaded the development of the Men's forum group in my local church.

Actively participated in the Client-side development of a school management system. Responsible for the development of the client side section of a Non – Governmental Foundation (SeeJoy Foundation)

#### **EDUCATION and PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

BSc (Computer Science)
Udacity React Nano degree Program
Hotels.ng Internship (HNGi) 6.0 Finalist. (Frontend Developer)

Reference available upon request